<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tool on Diy &amp; Code</title><link>https://mydiy.space/tags/tool/</link><description>Recent content in Tool on Diy &amp; Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 14:27:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mydiy.space/tags/tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>T12 Soldering Station</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/t12-soldering-station/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 14:27:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/t12-soldering-station/</guid><description>After long wait for all parts and some unsuccessful drilling of alu cases from China I have finished T12 controller. Station works from 12V - 24V and has light indication which indicates how high is temperature by speed of blinking. It starts with red color on lowest and as it heats up it changes to green color when it reaches selected temperature.
Station is made of DC input socket, 10K potentiometer, GX12 socket for connecting iron, on/off switch, aluminium case and 616dev controller.</description></item><item><title>Crimp Tool</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/crimp-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 13:19:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/crimp-tool/</guid><description>After I got wire stripping tool I felt need to get crimp tool so I can make my own connections. Crimp tool was around $12 and it is doing what its supposed to do. It can crimp in ranges 0.1 - 0.5mm, 0.5 - 1.5mm, 1.5 - 2.5mm and 4 - 6mm. Crimping 2.2mm spade connector and dupont female connector were successful after few tries.
Harden 6606420 Long time ago I bought some button switches that uses spade connectors to connect wires to it and those will be used for diy T12 soldering station project.</description></item><item><title>New Tool</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/new-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:44:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/new-tool/</guid><description>I wanted and needed this tool for a long time. It is one of the most important tool for professionals and hobbyist and it is not that expensive, it costs around $10. This tool comes in many variations and versions but I think this one is best because it have blunt jaws and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut wire strands, it just rips wire insulation.
It is called automatic wire stripper and can be bought on Ebay or Aliexpress or in local stores.</description></item></channel></rss>