<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Diy &amp; Code</title><link>https://mydiy.space/</link><description>Recent content on Diy &amp; Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:02:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mydiy.space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Component Tester</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/component-tester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:02:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/component-tester/</guid><description>This tool is one of the most used in every workshop, got it from ebay for around 10$ and after calibration it is pretty accurate. There are versions that use single 18650 battery but those were more expensive that this. Why I got this tester is that ih has connector for leads so I dont need always to use provided socket. That will hopefully make it last longer.
I have used it very much but it has secret menu with many additional options like signal generator and so on.</description></item><item><title>New Multimeter</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/new-multimeter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 09:53:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/new-multimeter/</guid><description>I have got this new multimeter for around 15$ and its almost perfect. In comparing to ANENG multimeters that are often more expensive this one is doing even more than them.
It has nice big display, very quick response, it can detect voltage without contact and has flashlight. One thing that I like and was big plus while searching which one to order was that this multimeter is using 3 x AAA battery instead of 9V battery.</description></item><item><title>Iot Dashboard</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/iot-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 08:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/iot-dashboard/</guid><description>I am currently working on project that should be a dashboard for IOT sensors. Is it based on microservices structure with services running on NodeJS with MySQL database, communicating between via RabbitMQ as orchestrator. Only log service should be different by using InfluxDB to store data received via MQTT broker : client flow.
I want to completely write it in Typescript and to try to develop services inside containers using VSCode remote plugins and it was very nice experience so far.</description></item><item><title>T12 Soldering Station</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/t12-soldering-station/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 14:27:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/t12-soldering-station/</guid><description>After long wait for all parts and some unsuccessful drilling of alu cases from China I have finished T12 controller. Station works from 12V - 24V and has light indication which indicates how high is temperature by speed of blinking. It starts with red color on lowest and as it heats up it changes to green color when it reaches selected temperature.
Station is made of DC input socket, 10K potentiometer, GX12 socket for connecting iron, on/off switch, aluminium case and 616dev controller.</description></item><item><title>Crimp Tool</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/crimp-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 13:19:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/crimp-tool/</guid><description>After I got wire stripping tool I felt need to get crimp tool so I can make my own connections. Crimp tool was around $12 and it is doing what its supposed to do. It can crimp in ranges 0.1 - 0.5mm, 0.5 - 1.5mm, 1.5 - 2.5mm and 4 - 6mm. Crimping 2.2mm spade connector and dupont female connector were successful after few tries.
Harden 6606420 Long time ago I bought some button switches that uses spade connectors to connect wires to it and those will be used for diy T12 soldering station project.</description></item><item><title>Log</title><link>https://mydiy.space/log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 21:51:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/log/</guid><description> 2020-10-22 - Added new posts. 2020-10-14 - Added new post. 2020-01-26 - Added new post. 2019-12-13 - Added new post. 2019-10-10 - Added new post. 2019-10-09 - Changed blog title and done some fixes. 2019-10-08 - Changed style of some pages and fixed gallery bug. 2019-10-07 - Added new posts and fixed some bugs. 2019-10-07 - Website uploaded.</description></item><item><title>New Tool</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/new-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:44:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/new-tool/</guid><description>I wanted and needed this tool for a long time. It is one of the most important tool for professionals and hobbyist and it is not that expensive, it costs around $10. This tool comes in many variations and versions but I think this one is best because it have blunt jaws and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut wire strands, it just rips wire insulation.
It is called automatic wire stripper and can be bought on Ebay or Aliexpress or in local stores.</description></item><item><title>Building Vu Meter</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/building-vu-meter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:43:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/building-vu-meter/</guid><description>I like vintage audio equipment and my favorite thing are cassette decks with vu meters. When I was planing to build my audio amplifier I always knew that front panel must contain vu meters.
On Aliexpress and Ebay many vu meters can be found but most of them are just voltage meters, to get real vu meters we need to salvage them from old decks. Luckily decks can be found dirt cheap.</description></item><item><title>Website Upload Script</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/website-upload-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:42:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/website-upload-script/</guid><description>Uploading website file by file using ftp programs can be very boring and tedious. That&amp;rsquo;s why I have tried to simplify that process.
I have found script called Unzipper that I am going to use for this project - you can download it here.
Plan is to zip or rar (if your hosting allows that) your website and use unzipper script to extract it. Its all plain and simple, it was only needed to modify few lines in unzipper code.</description></item><item><title>Micropython Ota Function</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/micropython-ota-function/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:40:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/micropython-ota-function/</guid><description>I assume you have built your esp-open-sdk and you know how to compile micropython firmware, if you dont know how check older posts. Installation procedure goes like this.
Download yaota8266 and axtls repositories.
Create esp8266ota folder and extract yaota8266 repository in it. Then navigate to esp8266ota/yaota8266/ota_server/lib/axtls and extract axtls repository there. I have tried to clone yaota8266 repository but it was giving me empty axtls folder so I had to do it manually.</description></item><item><title>Micropython Frozen Modules</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/micropython-frozen-modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:39:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/micropython-frozen-modules/</guid><description>Last time we finished building custom micropython firmware for esp8266 and now we are going to add our custom modules to it.
Frozen modules are very good option if you are low on memory as I was with one project. Other useful thing is you don&amp;rsquo;t need to upload those files on to rom, they will always be there.
Open port/esp8266 folder and put your python files into modules directory.</description></item><item><title>Python Ftp Uploader</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/python-ftp-uploader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:38:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/python-ftp-uploader/</guid><description>I have created this uploader first as a practice and secondly so I can use it to upload my website. Basicly script at start checks if directory is hashed, if it&amp;rsquo;s not directory will be hashed, hash file will be created with hash value in it. Then script will proceed to upload selected directory content to target server.
If hash file exist at start script will rehash directory and compare its hash with hash from existing hash file.</description></item><item><title>Build Micropython Firmware</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/build-micropython-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:35:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/build-micropython-firmware/</guid><description>During building apps for esp8266 boards in micropython I have stumbled across many problems, one problem that was most anoying is memory errors.
Naturally I started searching how to fix those problems and people mentioned few solutions. They have mentioned precompiling source files and that didn&amp;rsquo;t help me. Then they mentioned freezing files into esp8266 flash, that means integrating your own python packages into firmware of your board.
I started exploring that solution and that is why I&amp;rsquo;m making this guide.</description></item><item><title>Php Based Rest Api</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/php-based-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:34:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/php-based-rest-api/</guid><description>For almost every communication esp is doing to the web api is needed, so I tought why don&amp;rsquo;t I build one. I familiarized myself with with what are crucial options api needs to do to be called rest and I think this one does all of that.
I have found a lot info online how to start, how to handle main methods as post, get, put, delete and how every method controls their functions.</description></item><item><title>Email Notifications With Esp Board</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/email-notifications-with-esp-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:32:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/email-notifications-with-esp-board/</guid><description>I wanted to create simple notification script that will notify me when my board detects new software version on github by email.
I have tried few smtp micropython libraries and they throw me errors all the time so I opted for simpler solution to create my php script that will send received data as notification to my email.
&amp;lt;?php $_POST = json_decode(file_get_contents(&amp;#39;php://input&amp;#39;), true); $link = $_POST[&amp;#39;link&amp;#39;]; $name = $_POST[&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;]; $version = $_POST[&amp;#39;version&amp;#39;]; $to = &amp;#39;put target email here&amp;#39;; $subject = &amp;#34;New version of $nameis available for download.</description></item><item><title>Post Data to Website Using Esp Board</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/post-data-to-website-using-esp-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:29:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/post-data-to-website-using-esp-board/</guid><description>Having many of these boards and wanted to learn micropython, I have decided to make little project and to use esp8266 board to send some data to my website from where I can access it any time or place I want. They are very cheap and can be bought for around $2 on Aliexpress.
Biggest problem I have encountered was when whatever I send to server php did&amp;rsquo;t show anything. I tought it is problem in my python code so I have changed it few times, tried to use post and get dump websites to see how my post request looks and all looked fine.</description></item><item><title>Up and Running</title><link>https://mydiy.space/posts/up-and-running/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 20:28:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/posts/up-and-running/</guid><description>My idea behind this website is that I want to share my diy projects and I think this is the best way. All projects will be linked to github repository where you will be able to download project and try it for yourself.
My main goal with all this is to learn more about electronics and python programming.
https://github.com/nenadfilipovic</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://mydiy.space/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 19:54:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mydiy.space/about/</guid><description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m very passionate about electronics and diy so you can expect to see posts about that here.
Also I will post about programming, especially in javascript and some python and programming esp boards using micropython.
You can contact me at contact@mydiy.space.
My github activity</description></item></channel></rss>